hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the TSA automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
test automation obstacles with trient
tosa let's look at our next obstacle
which is called halfway now this is a
pretty simple obstacle if you know how
to um steer this particular control so
here we need to click in the right half
of the button so it's quite a long
button and here we need to click it on
the right half of this okay so if I
click it here you will see that uh the
automation obstacle is completed if I
click here then nothing will happen Okay
so this is what uh we need to do now in
order to do this we need to use uh
something called called offset for the
click
operation so what this particular offset
is
right so uh we can uh Define
offsets for two types of Click
operations okay and these are for the
click method and also for the long click
method okay so uh we know already uh
what the click operation does the long
click using this particular uh operation
you can basically click with your left
Mouse click and it will remain for at
least 2 seconds okay so if you want uh
to click on a button for a longer amount
of time then you can use this long click
and then we can also Define offset for
both of this click operations for
clicking and also long clicking right
now this opt ET uh syntax how you can do
this is you need to first right click
okay and then you need to mention uh
either the offset horizontal or offset
vertical okay so this is basically a
offset position either in your
horizontal axis or in the vertical axis
okay so this is how the syntax looks
like now um how can we uh basically use
this here right so since we have to uh
click on the right hand side of this
particular button we can provide um
either an offset in terms of pixels okay
or uh we can also provide it in uh terms
of percentage okay so in this case uh we
will go ahead and uh we will try to use
um percentage
so that we can click on the right half
of this particular button so let's see
how we can do this in
tosa okay so uh first let's create our
module here so we'll scan the module as
usual we'll go to obstacles folder and
go to scan
application so here I just need to uh
scan this particular control which is
the button itself and then um I am going
to close this and save this
module okay um so now uh we can create
our test case to automate this
particular step so we will create a new
test case
here and then uh I'm going to add that
particular particular module right
here okay as I said uh it's a pretty
simple one um we just need to make sure
that we are using the offset here okay
instead of simple click
operation so here uh we are going to
write the expression uh as I said we
have to use the click operation but then
inside this uh we need to mention the
offset okay and uh what I'm going to do
is I'm going to mention something like
90% okay so uh what it will do is uh it
will try to uh click on the right hand
side of uh the button okay to complete
this particular obstacle so let's go
ahead and Mark it as
completed and then um let's go ahead and
try to run
this okay so as you can see it is trying
to click on the uh right hand corner of
this particular button which will be
like an uh percentage of uh the complete
area of the button and I am clicking on
the 90 percentage which is more on the
right hand side if you want to click on
the left hand side then it will be more
of uh in the range of 10 to 50
percentage and if you want to just click
on the center then you can directly use
uh the normal click operation it will be
enough to click on that particular
button so the same offset operation can
also be applied to the long click method
uh these are for buttons where you have
problems clicking on it or it takes more
time to click on those particular
buttons or you have to click on a
particular position of any particular uh
button or a link right so this is how
you can use the offset uh position on
your click operations to solve this
particular automation
problem that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video